《斯巴达克斯：血与沙》
《牺牲之剑》
Sura
Sura.
罗马人来的时候
When the Romans came …
我以为再也看不到你了
never thought see her again.
嘘 我会永远和你在一起
I will always be with you.
神也不能把我从你身边带走
Not even the gods I would take your side.
如果他们敢试的话 我就把他们全杀了
I would kill all if they tried.
把他们带到澡堂
Take them to the bathroom.
但他妈的先把头发剪了
But before we cut these hairs.
主人
Dominus.
泳池干了 是呀 我们需要雨水
The tank is empty. Yes, we need rain.
用钱就能让它装满水
Money also would fill.
我们也需要它
We need it too.
你的新宠物怎么样？活着
How is your new puppy? Breathe.
用掉的钱可以让泳池装满一个月
With the money paid for it would fill
你用太多的钱了…
the tank for a month. Spent too much …
物有所值 Lucretia 斯巴达克斯只是个活死人
I paid my worth, Lucretia. Spartacus is an undead.
在他死之前
How long until he dies,
还有多久你才能拿回你的投资？
taking with him your investment?
他就要完成他的使命了
Not before he achieve their goals.
Claudius Glaber副将给的
Do Legadus Claudius glaber.
他的目的是什么？和我希望的一样
What are his intentions? Similar to what I expected.
他要来 两天内
He will come here. In two days.
他来的意图不明显
The reason for the visit unclear.
但是意思很明显 他要来谢我
It is, but the meaning is Clearly, he has to thank me.
为什么？
Why?
为了色雷斯人付了太多钱？
Since they paid more expensive the Thracian?
Glaber试图在竞技场杀了他 斯巴达克斯逃过一劫
Spartacus escaped the attempt glaber to assassinate him.
人们想要让他自由
The people asked for his release.
这让副将很为难
That left in an embarrassing situation.
我提议买下他 两全其美
When you buy it, I offering an alternative.
就是价格虚高了点
At a high price.
如果斯巴达克斯渎了神还能活下来
If Spartacus survive the oath
竞技场会是他的坟墓
the arena will be your grave it should have been.
如果没活下来
If not survive …
他早一点死副将会很高兴的
His death will be a pleasure premature for the Legadus.
唔 欲望还蛮高涨的嘛
Wishes of both be satisfied.
我需要一点帮忙
I need a little help.
副将简单的感谢不足够
A simple gesture of gratitude the Legadus not enough.
我们需要他的支持
What we want is his support.
不能更少了
No less than that.
副将会是我们的施主
The Legadus as our benefactor.
他的钱会让我们的泳池满到溢出来的
The coins will fill it reservoir to overflowing.
我们需要准备一个宴会 是的 但是小型的
We will make a feast. Yes, but small.
有酒有水 很多水
With wine and water, of water.
足够让舌头湿润了
Just enough … to wet the tongue.
我会献祭一头牛让天神保佑我们的
Sacrifice a bull to have the favor of the gods.
来只小一点的嘛 …
Maybe something smaller …
一头羊吗？
A sheep?
献给众神 愿他们保佑我们好运
May the gods bless us lucky.
这头他妈的的猪还活着
Mother fucker … damn that pig still alive.
他就是斯巴达克斯 大家都在谈论的人
That's him. The Spartacus who everyone is talking about.
斯巴达克斯？
Spartacus?
我名字是… 没有人关心你曾经是谁
My name is … No one cares who did it.
他现在是谁我也不在意
Not give a damn for who he is.
这是什么地方？来生 朋友
What is this place? Life after death, friend.
或者至少是在它生锈的门外
Or at least the outside rusty gates.
你现在是Batiatus的客人
You are a guest honored now Batiatus.
卡普阿伟大的Ludus的拥有者
Owner of great Ludus de Capua.
Ludus？
Ludus?
训练学校
School training,
将男人转变为天神的地方
where men are transformed into gods.
血液是他们的甜浆 竞技场是他们的巅峰
Blood is the nectar of them. And the arena is the top.
角斗士
Gladiators.
最真的兄弟情谊
The most true brotherhood.
接下来几天你和其它新丁
Survive the coming days …
会成为我们的一分子
and you and the other recruits may live among us.
会被烙上这个烙印
And receive our brand.
然后我们能给你一点东西吗？
Meanwhile, we offer something?
食物 水 也许脚底的一些香油
Food, water. Maybe oil fragrant for your feet.
水
Water.
这家伙反应太慢 是不是？对色雷斯人你还期待什么？
This one is slow, is not it? What expect from a Thracian?
闻起来像一坨新鲜的狗屎
It smells like shit fresh.
所有人 除了他们女人
Everyone. Except their wives.
闻起来都像尿 还有狗屎
They smell of … piss. And shit.
你呢？是什么？
And you, what is?
我是高卢人 小子 最优秀的人种
I am a Frenchman, kid. The best of my race.
Crixus 打不败的
Crixus, the undefeated.
高卢人 这就解释了你为什么
A Frenchman. This explains why …
闻起来像女人
smells like woman.
小心你的伤口 吃饭吧 好好休息去
Take care of your wounds. Eat, rest.
你有力气的时候 我们再来谈这个
When retrieving the forces … back to that conversation.
弱者
Weak! Weak!
一群狗屎 都没鸡巴的
A lot of shit. It should not stick.
那你应该加入他们 混蛋
Then you should join them, asshole.
你们脚底下是什么？
What's underneath your feet?
回答
Answer!
你们脚底下是什么？
What's underneath your feet?
沙子
Sand.
Crixus 你脚底是什么？
Crixus, which is underneath your feet?
神圣的土地 导师
Holy ground, Doctor.
被泪水和鲜血浇灌的
Bathed in tears blood.
你们的眼泪 你们的鲜血
Your tears, your blood, pathetic lives
你们这群可悲的生命 要百炼才能成钢
forged into something of value.
好好听 好好学
Listen, learn, and maybe live …
也许能作为角斗士活下来
as gladiators!
现在 注意听你们主人的话
Now, pay attention on his master.
你们已经被保佑了 所有这里的每一位
You were blessed, each one of you …
在这里找到自己 Quintus Lentulus Batiatus的Ludus学校
for being here in Ludus Quintus Lentulus Batiatus.
为共和国准备最优秀的角斗士
That comes from the best all the gladiators!
在接下来的日子里证明自己
Prove value in the difficult days ahead.
不仅仅是个普通的奴隶 不仅仅是个男人
Stems are more than slaves, more than men.
失败 就是死亡
Fail and die …
留在这里或者被卖去挖煤
Well where they are or will be sent to the mines.
成功 骄傲地站在我太阳神的余晖下
Triumph and stand up proud with my Titans!
Batiatus！Batiatus！Batiatus！
Batiatus! Batiatus! Batiatus!
作为角斗士 他不害怕死亡
A gladiator … not fear death.
他拥抱它 爱抚它
He embraces, caresses …
操它
The fode.
他每次进入竞技场
Each time he enters arena …
他把他的鸡巴放入野兽的嘴里
He puts his cock the mouth of the beast.
祈祷在它嘴巴闭上之前 他能回家
And pray to return home before her mouth shut.
你们这群狗没有一个能坚持一会的
None of you dogs last a moment.
除了一个
Except one.
这个可悲的色雷斯人
This sad piece of Thracian
被判了死刑 只有一把剑
survived against four men in the arena.
在竞技场打败了四个人
Sentenced to death. With nothing but a sword to trust your life.
他们打倒他
Came to him …
一次 一次又一次
Again, again and again.
他战胜了死亡 信念还有众神
He defied death, the fate and the gods themselves.
必须看看这个人 好好研究他 然后发现…
Must see this man, study it and understand …
他其实什么也不是
it is nothing.
一个懦夫 一个辅助部队的逃兵
A coward, a deserter auxiliary troops.
他在竞技场的胜利和他的勇气一样空洞无力
His victory in the arena was as empty as his courage.
他打败了Solonius未经训练的手下
He fought against men poorly trained Solonius,
你主人的敌人
the rival of his master.
如果他和这里任何一个角斗士进入竞技场的话
If it had entered the arena any gladiator here,
他的人头早就落地了
his head would not have been from your body.
这个色雷斯人不同意
The Thracian disagrees.
或许来个证明吧？
A demonstration, perhaps.
Crixus！
Crixus!
练习剑
Swords of training.
证明我们是错的 斯巴达克斯
Prove us wrong, Spartacus.
捡起来
Take it.
斯巴达克斯！
Spartacus!
那不是我的名字
This is not my name.
你的名字 你的人生 由我们来决定
Your name, your life, is what we decide.
也许这个懦夫需要一点优势
Perhaps the coward wants some advantage
来让发抖的脚停下来
to stop shaking knees.
Cledius
Cledius.
拿起来
Take it.
这个人我无能为力了
I can not do anything with this one.
把他送到矿井去
Send him to the mines.
很急 是吗？
We seem in a hurry, right?
进攻必须有合适的立足点
An attack must be made the right foundation.
在身体恢复平衡前得给人施加点压力
He tends to push before winning balance.
Crixus
允许在你背部占有优势 你就死定了
Let advantage on his back and you will be condemned.
跟比你强大的对手缠斗 你就完蛋了
Test forces with an opponent more powerful and will be dead.
在竞技场再甩一次剑 你就再死一次
Throw your sword into the arena and you'll be dead again.
你的愚蠢让他丧了命
His folly has cost a life.
但你的命还没有赎完罪
But its still can be redeemed.
举两个手指 投降的意思
Two fingers. A sign of redemption.
请求占绝对上风的人宽容
A plea for mercy responsible for the games.
求我们饶命呀 小子
Beg for your life rabbit.
杀了他
Finish him.
Crixus！
Crixus!
主人 继续训练
Dominus. Keep your workout.
他试图杀害你最好的角斗士 你却让他活着？
He tried to kill his best man and you let him live?
Glaber明天到访
Glaber visit us tomorrow.
他有意让这个色雷斯人生不如死
His intentions with the Thracian include blood
他满意之前
and until they are satisfied
我得让他活着
I intend to keep it warm and flowing.
神呀 太热了
God, it's hot.
从头到舌跟沸腾了一样
Good boiling language and the head.
吃吧
Eat!
狗屁都不是的奴隶和罪犯 大部分
Slaves of shit and criminals. Many of them.
我们比较好？
We are best?
你在执刑时活下来
Survived their implementation.
两次 加上那个高卢人
Twice, counting that the Gaul
没把你头塞进沙子
not present their brains to the sand.
你不同
You're from a different source.
比这群倒霉鬼强
Above this band of unfortunates.
你呢？
And you?
Varro
Varro.
最惨的一个
The worst of all.
自由人 自作孽
A free man, sentenced by their own hands.
为什么有人自愿来做这个？
Why condemn a man voluntarily to that?
一些小债
Some small debts …
利滚利
Grew.
还钱很困难
Pay them was difficult.
我唯一担心的是…
If only affects me …
你有家人？老婆和小孩
You have family? Wifeand child.
男孩
A boy.
在竞技场呆两年 赢了钱让他们生活
2 years in the arena, and my earnings to sustain.
赢钱？
Gains?
如果你打得好的话 有钱奖赏
If you fight well, is rewarded in cash.
够还钱的了 如果众神眷顾的话
Enough to pay my debts, if the gods want.
众神
Gods …
你真笨
You're a fool.
经鉴定还是个好伙伴
And in good company, it seems.
这是我目前能做到的
It's the best I can now.
一两个还有希望 但其它的
1 or 2 promising but other
我妈都不会把他们送到竞技场来 你没妈
my mother would not send the arena. You have no mother.
她生你下就抛弃你了 这就是为什么我喜欢你
He left the cunt beyond, why is my favorite!
没有更好的吗？
No better offer?
更好的 是呀 但就我的钱来说 没有
Better, yes, that fits in my pocket, no.
你站出来质疑和抱怨 而不是去做好你的事情
It is challenging and demanding instead of devoting themselves to the task.
我不仅效忠你Batiatus 还有Ludus
I insist only to honor him, Batiatus, and this Ludus.
Glaber副将明天到访
The Legadus glaber come tomorrow
带着让他重建的愿景
and with him hope best of luck, until then
在此之前 我只能负担得起这些废物
these men are what I pay.
把他们训练好
Turn them into rocks …
不然就把他们丢到矿里去
or throw them in the mines.
你的意愿 我来做
His will, my hands.
Ovidius 抱歉有事耽搁了
Ovidius, I apologize the delay.
看在钱的份上 原谅你
I accept the apology currencies.
3个月的粮食 钱还没付呢
3 months of grains payments are late.
3个月 是吗？到今天
3? Really? Exactly.
Vulcanalia的比赛就要举行了
Kits Vulcanalia are coming
我到时候可以还钱
could be extended debt by then.
本金上涨30% 30%
The debt-most 30%."Thirty?
要不现在还钱？
Or pay the debt now.
Vulcanalia之后本金上涨30%
The debt plus 30% after Vulcanalia.
明天开始
Next day.
我可以打败他 Crixus？
I could beat him. Crixus?
你会被打得屁滚尿流
You would have shit all.
我不会惨到那个地步 他妈的像狗一样
Would not have finished on the floor fucked like a dog!
没有训练 那个高卢人 可以打败我们随便哪个 Kerza
Without training, the Gaul defeat all of us, Kerze.
讲其它就没意义了
To say otherwise is nonsense.
我祈祷最后测试里不要遇到Crixus
I pray not face Crixus the final test.
别担心 你走不了那么远 混小子
Do not worry, not come so far, asshole.
每个人都能参加测试
Everyone can get the test.
之后呢？
And beyond.
自由
Freedom.
总有一天 如果打得好的话
One day, to fight well.
自由
Freedom.
如果你拿钱的话 你不能选择自由的 Varro
Worthless if you have money, Varro.
赢得竞技场观众的心 你两样都可得到
Win the hearts of audiences the arena and will have both.
你在那和角斗士打过？
He fought with the gladiators there.
你觉得我们的机率有多大？
What are our chances?
全部都会死
All will die.
起来
Stand!
小子 证明自己是男人之后再睡觉
Sleep when they prove are men.
接着转
Continue to march.
很晚了
It's late.
是呀
Is even.
回去你的梦乡吧 马上
Back to your dreams. In a minute.
我们需要更好的酒 我们需要很多东西
We need better wine. We need several things.
我们会重新得到的
As we will again.
都安排好了吗？我都打点好了
Is everything ready? I took care of everything.
我们明天不能有闪失
We can not fail tomorrow.
如果有了Glaber的支持…
Achieve the support glaber …
会的
Will.
怎么这么确定？
How sure?
我们做了我们能做的 现在就交给众神了
We did our best, is now in the hands of the gods.
睡觉吧
Come to bed.
把那杯差劲的酒拿来
And bring the wine horrible.
我请求你们
I beg you.
别给我搞砸了
I do not fuck.
停下来
Stop!
今天的训练马上开始
Soon begins training day.
吃饭
Eat!
鸟人 现在一整天都训练？
Cock Jupiter! Now we train all day?
还相信所有人能活到测试？
Still believes that all survive to prove?
大部分
Almost all.
你还是个笨蛋
It is still a fool, then.
Batiatus付钱买的他们？
Batiatus paid these men?
就外表来看 没花多少
Very little the appearance of them.
罗马的生存之道就是钱
The way Roman lives for money.
一些人注定比其它人更有钱
Some are worth more others.
我听说有些色雷斯人很贵
I heard that some Thracian cost expensive.
我看价格还在涨
I think the price rise even more.
我还记得我是新丁的时候 行走有多艰难
I remember how hard it was the march when he was recruiting.
一定饿疯了
They must be mad with hunger.
填饱你们肚子
Fill your belly.
妈的
Crap.
要再寻死的时候告我一声
Wake me in time to die again.
食物的事情我道歉
I apologize for the food.
Barca那家伙只是搞笑
Barca think delicious.
至少没往里边撒尿 那样子更吃不下
Do not eat in this joint, is less.
日子会很艰难的 没有东西吃的话…
The days will be difficult. No food.
就更惨了 你会给我你的面包？
Always worse. Gave me your bread?
我的？不是
My? No.
我把东西从这搬到那 这只手转那只手 即使是墙外的东西
I move things from here to there, even outside these walls.
你要让什么 让我提供
Everything you need, Ashur can.
我不要 兄弟
Not owe anyone.
我不求回报的
I ask nothing in return.
我唯一关心的是你接下来几天的力气
My only concern is its strength in the coming days.
有话直说
And how to escape from here?
几句话就说清楚了
I tried once …
我还提供其它服务 我让人下注
Other services I offer: probabilities.
谁生谁死？多快多慢？
Who lives and who dies, how quickly or slowly,
哪一天或什么时候
what day or time.
比赛是用来消磨时间和金钱的
Games to spend time and money.
我呢？12：1的机率去矿上
What about give me? 12 To 1 in favor of mines.
比死的机率高
Highest to die.
你顶得住的话 Crixus会输一笔钱
Crixus lose much if it is against the numbers.
我看好你哟
If I were you, would not go so well.
别认为我把你当朋友？
Do not think I am your friend.
想都别想
Do not even think about it.
你怎么拿到的？
How did you get?
下注呗
Defying odds.
我怕会血本无归啊
I fear they are about to get worse.
Glaber 叫我的官职 副将
, Glaber. Call me Legadus.
还是个畜牲 老样子
Even an animal … The mark of his race.
她在哪？谁？
Where is she? Who?
那个小媳妇？
Your woman.
在哪？我高兴在哪就在哪儿
Where? Where do I want.
她没对你造成任何伤害
She did him no harm.
是呀 没有
True. None.
但是 你伤害了我
But you … You did me wrong.
带着辅助部队逃了
Took auxiliaries desertion,
质疑我的命令
questioned my orders.
让我在参议员面前颜面扫地
It ruined my reputation Senate.
然后呢 在竞技场 你再一次伤害了我
And then, the Arena, hurt me again
让我不能让你去死
not knowing when to die.
用我的命
My life, so …
去换她
In exchange for her.
你的命已经不能用来谈条件了
His life is no longer his to negotiate.
如果我要你去死 只要轻轻一声
If I wanted to get her I need only whisper,
Batiatus会下令的
and the good Batiatus give the order.
那在他耳边大叫命令呀
Then give the command in his ear.
你误解了我 色雷斯人
Has a misconception me, Thracian.
没错 因为你的无礼我想让你去死
True. Ever wanted his death in exchange for their disrespect.
但是我看到一个问题
But now I that was a mistake.
我们不应该结束太快
Would like to … It would be too fast.
现在我的愿望变得血腥了…
Now my desires turned to blood …
看着你的血一点点流干
Poured drop by drop, until it is exhausted.
我告诉过你罗马的影响力很大
I told him that the shadow of Rome was vast.
你会死在这上面的 被撕成碎片
And die under it, piece by piece,
听到人民的嘲笑
the roar of the crowd.
- 离别的恩惠 - 让你能记住我
- A parting kindness … - To bind us.
我从她大腿取下来的
I took it from her thigh.
为了保留这个气味
To preserve the scent.
在我的手下用他们的气味玷污之前
Before my men to contaminate with their smell.
不要
No!
真好玩呀
It was fun, 7.
当她的眼里不再有斗志
And when the fight finally let your eyes
我用半块钱币
sold it for a Syrian unpleasant
就把她卖给了叙利亚人
currency by half.
这个色雷斯人终于认清 他在我面前的位置了
The Thracian finally learned place in front of me.
跪下了
Knees.
探访色雷斯人还满意吗？
The visit to the Thracian satisfactory?
一个我不屑一顾的人
Man I do not care anymore.
管他呢
Do not talk more about it.
我们为您准备了宴会
Prepared a feast you.
我要去罗马 罗马？现在？
Postpartum to Rome. Rome? Now?
旅途中要点什么东西呢？
Something for the trip, then?
你真的不应该这么麻烦的 Lucretia
There should have been given work, Lucretia.
这些寻常小菜让我胃不舒服
These common dishes irritate my stomach.
等你夫君的时候 要不要来点酒呢？
Maybe a little wine? While we hope your husband.
花味的吗？不是 但尝起来一样
Flavored? No. But taste the same.
那来点水吧
Water, then.
这么热还有那些沙尘 是不是永远都不下雨了
The heat and dust! It will rain again?
我们只能祈祷
We can only pray.
我一踏上卡普阿的街道
I can not put your feet the streets of Capua
就听到有人在祈求老天下一点雨
without hearing someone begging to heaven by a drizzle.
众神还是无视我们
And yet the gods ignore us.
也许我们做了触犯他们的事情
Maybe we did something that offended.
我每天都有努力做点事的
I try to do a little something every day.
所以你就是源头 Ilithyia
So you're the cause, Ilithyia.
我得收敛点了
I would stay away.
丘比特随时都能射出他的情箭
Jupiter could launch a thunder at any time.
他得有所选择
He would have to choose between two targets.
我觉得我是罗马女人中最守妇道的
And I thought being in the presence a Roman respectable.
守妇道这个词是男人发明
Respectable is a word invented by men,
用来奴役我们的
that seek to enslave us her.
你之前来过Ludus里吗？没有
"I've been to a Ludus? No.
我一直想要来看看 但父亲总是不允许
Always wanted but my father never left.
你不听他话的？
And you obey his orders.
也不是全部啦 我丈夫的也是
Not all, nor those of my husband.
被这些畜牲的噪音和气味包围
How to live with the noise and the smell? Surrounded by these …
你怎么活得下来？
Animals.
是呀 他们原始又野蛮 是吧？
Yes, they are savage and brutal, are not they?
有点精神失常
Seem out of a delirium.
你不担心吗？
You do not care?
如果他们全疯了 不成嗜血怪物了么？
And if they were all crazy, crying for blood?
Ludus是我丈夫祖上一代代传下来的
This family is Ludus my husband for generations,
仍然屹立不倒
and still standing.
那你的孩子呢？你会让他们和他们玩吗？
And their children? Lets play with them?
我没有小孩
I have no children.
对不起 我以为像你这种年纪的女人…
Sorry. I thought that a woman their age …
走吧 去罗马
Come, let's go to Rome.
这么快？我们能呆会吗？
So soon? We can get a little?
我想看看角斗士
I want to watch the gladiators.
下次 走吧
Another time, come on.
Kerza
Kerza.
和斯巴达克斯玩一玩 好的 导师
Make-double with Spartacus."Yes, Doctor.
新丁们 注意
Recruits! Watch!
给这个色雷斯人秀秀他不在时 我们学的东西
Show the Thracian we learn in his absence.
第一场 进攻
Act One! Attack!
第二场 进攻
Act Two! Attack!
斯巴达克斯！
Spartacus!
众神一整天都不待见我
The gods did not piss on me enough for one day?
他妈的 Glaber副将轻视我 把我当成普通奴隶
The Legadus glaber despise me as a slave,
但不止 还要屎上撒泡尿 倒进嘴里…
but no, let's join shit the piss. And pour the mouth …
如果他们知道Batiatus不能
If they know that Batiatus not
控制自己手下
control their men.
我警告过你… 你什么也没警告
I had warned … "No tell me anything!
商量后 承诺说「你的意愿 我来做」
You will advise and make promises as "my hands, his will."
副将差点就进了我的门
The evil was Legadus Cum in my gates.
那个色雷斯人太难把握了 那就教他我们的规矩
The Thracian is unpredictable. Teach him our rules!
鞭抽棍打都没用
Cane and whip do not wash.
他是个畜牲 最好把他送进矿山
It is an animal, is better to send him mine!
不行 其他人还少花了钱
No, the other cost little.
但斯巴达克斯太值钱了
But Spartacus worth much more.
他比这些人加起来还值钱
Its value is much higher the sum of the others.
我得有回报
Can I return one.
不是从副将那 而是从这个人这里 即使他难以把握？
If the Legadus, himself. Even though unpredictable?
他充满激情
It is full of passion.
也能把别人鼓动起来 很能挑起观众热情
But it infuriated is equal to others
得找方法驯服他
a gift to the public to find out how to tame it.
他拼命挣扎来得到这个东西
Struggled to recover that piece of cloth.
即便在卫兵打他的时候
Even when the guards beat him.
也许能用得上
May prove useful.
这东西在副将来的时候在他手上
This was with Legadus, saw when he arrived.
把他带到我房间
Bring him to my room.
我来查清楚
Try to find what it is.
你为什么会在这？
Why are you here?
在这个地方 吃住我的
In that place under my hospitality.
你知道为什么吗？
You know why?
因为我信任了罗马
For trusted in honor of Rome.
你能在这是因为我祖父
You are here because my grandfather.
他创建了Ludus
He built this Ludus.
他相信没有人是无价的
Believed that no man is worthless.
但即便是最暴力的野兽 也能赢得尊敬和荣耀
Even in the most violent is honor and glory.
他把这个信念传给了我父亲 我父亲又把它传给了我
And these beliefs my father gave me.
我是个兼职角斗士教练
I am a "lanista.
跟我的先辈们一样 角斗士教练
As my father, a trainer of gladiators …
我看到这些人失去的东西
I think things in men they even lost.
一点火花 一点余烬
A spark, an ember.
我给他们一口气直到竞技场的那夜
And take care of her until igniting the arena.
我只为我自己的理由燃烧
Do not burn for another cause is not mine.
那是什么？
And what would it be?
钱？
Money?
就这一点而言你花了我不少
From this point of view cost me a lot …
这个应该不是理由
There are reasons simple …
职位 权力 爱情？
A position, power, love?
你有女人 色雷斯人
There's a woman, Thracian?
我有老婆 你爱她吗？
"I have a wife. The love?
当然 我能从你眼睛里看出来 而且牙关咬得紧紧地
Of course, I can see in his eyes.
这朵娇嫩的鲜花叫什么？
What is the name this delicate flower?
Sura 她在哪
Sura. Where is she?
他找到我的时候 把她从我身边抢走了
He took me when I was imprisoned.
Glaber副将 在他手上？
It takes by Legadus glaber?
他把她卖给叙利亚人
He sold for a Syrian.
你怎么知道他还活着？
How do you know it still alive?
你怎么知道我的心脏还在我胸腔跳动？
How do you know that the heart still beats in your chest?
大多数时候 我不知道
On most days, I do not know.
我只是一个简单的罗马人
I'm just a simple Roman.
虽然众神 政治家 恶棍是蛇鼠一窝
You try to follow his path, despite the will of the gods …
但还是得跟他们抗争…
Political …
努力闯出自己的一片天
Bandidos, although sometimes I can not tell …
但是你 你是最危险的动物
But you is the most dangerous animals.
发自内心的野兽
A beast with a heart.
再次拥抱你妻子的时候你会怎么做？
What would you do to insure his wife again?
感受她皮肤的温暖 亲吻她
To feel the warmth of your skin? To prove their lips?
你会杀人吗？
Kill for it?
拦在我们中间的人？
Who was among us.
杀多少呢？100个
How many, 100?
1000个？我会杀了全部
1000? It would kill everyone.
那上竞技场吧
So do the arena!
为了我和我祖先的荣耀
Fight for me and for the honor of my ancestors.
证明自己 登山巅峰 争取自己的自由
Prove yourself, get to the apex and win their freedom.
然后得到你失去的那个女人
Of course, the woman he lost.
我没有失去她
I have not lost.
她从我身边被人抢走的
She was taken from me.
一个人必须接受他的命运
A man has to accept destination …
或者被它打败
Or be destroyed by it.
为什么我要把我的命运 交到另一个罗马人手上？
Why do I put my fate the hands of another Roman?
因为他拿的东西
Because of that charge …
你妻子的？
It is your wife?
通过今晚的最后测试 谦卑而又不失尊严地
Pass the test tonight with honor and servitude.
叫我主人 我会帮你们重聚
Call me Dominus and will help them to meet.
选择权在你
The choice is yours.
停
Cease!
我想是平局 测试通过
I think a draw passed the test.
Barca！
Barca!
Marcus！
Marcus!
就位
In position!
开始
Begin!
真令人失望
That was disappointing.
不是每一次冒险都能得到高潮
Not every adventure ends in a climax.
每个女人都知道
A well-known for every woman.
Crixus！
Crixus!
斯巴达克斯！
Spartacus!
就位
In position!
最后一课 然后我会送你到来生
Last lesson before sending it beyond that.
开始
Begin!
操
Drugs.
是不是钱多人傻 就在此一举了
Expensive and useless everywhere.
打呀 色雷斯娘们
Fight, bitch Thracian.
眼泪？
Tears?
小兔子吓到屁滚尿流了
The rabbit is about to pee.
杀了这只小兔子
Kill the rabbit!
干掉他
Finish him!
色雷斯人
Thracians.
最后一课学到了
The lesson was well learned.
斯巴达克斯！
Spartacus!
停
Cease!
通过测试
Passed the test!
主人
Dominus.
你的生命从此有了意义
Your life now meaningless.
向我发誓
Swear to me.
背诵角斗士的誓言
Recite the oath Gladiator.
我把我的肉体 灵魂和意愿
I offer my flesh, my mind and my will,
献给伟大的Ludus
the glory of Ludus,
听从我主人的命令 Batiatus
and the will of my master, Batiatus.
接受烙印 束缚和挨打
Accepted be burned, chained, beaten …
为了誓言不惜生命
or die by that oath.
为了追求竞技场的荣耀
In search of honor the arena.
欢迎加入兄弟会
Welcome to the brotherhood.